hey guys this looks like a fun one we
have a square right here split up into
three regions and all three of them have
the same area and then we have a quarter
circle with a radius of 13 and the
question is asking what is the area of
the square if you want to try this on
your own pause it right now cuz I'm
going to solve it in 3 2 1 Let's copy
down and let's focus on the Square let's
label the sides of the square X so
ultimately we're trying to find X2 I
want to focus on this blue triangle
right here it has a base of X and let's
label the height Y and since the blue
area equals the red area equals the
green area we know that this triangle is
1/3 of the entire square area of this
triangle is 1/2 base time height where X
is the base and Y is the height for the
right hand side 1/3 of the square is
going to be 1/3 of x^2 next we can
multiply both sides by two on the left
hand side the 2 * 1/2 cancel so we just
have XY and on the right hand side the
two gets multiplied by the 1/3 to give
us 2/3 and then we can bring down the
x^2 next we we can divide both sides by
X and we can do that because we know X
is not equal to zero on the left hand
side we have y and on the right hand
side we have 2/3 of X so let's change
this y up here to 2/3 x and now let's
play around with a quarter Circle the
radius of this quarter circle is 13 and
that's going to be true all the way up
here so this length is equal to 13 and
that means the hypotenuse of our
triangle is also 13 and now we can do
Pythagorean theorem so we have A2 + B2 =
c^2 or in this case it's x^2 + 2/3 x^2
is equal to 132 we can bring down the
x^2 and then this squar is going to
distribute to both the 2/3 and the x
squared and then this squar is going to
distribute to both the two and the three
and that'll give us four nths and let's
smush everything together and set that
equal to 13 s which is 169 nice and now
let's combine like terms I want to give
these a common denominator so let's
multiply the x^2 by 9 over 9 so now
we're doing 9 9 + 4 9 which is 13 9 x^2
and that's still equal to 169 let's
multiply both sides by the reciprocal
9913 on the left hand side we just have
x^2 and on the right hand side we'll
have 117 and that's the answer to our
question the area of the square is 117
cm squared let's put a box around it how
exciting